# Denis R Newman-Griffis

Curriculum Vitae

The Ohio State University
2015 Neil Ave
Columbus, OH, USA

✓ denis.newman.griffis@gmail.com

✓ drgriffis.github.io

Natural Language Processing, Biomedical Informatics, Computational Semantics, Information Extraction, Machine Learning

#### **Publications**

- 2017 Denis Newman-Griffis, Albert M Lai, and Eric Fosler-Lussier. Insights into Analogy Completion from the Biomedical Domain. In *Proceedings of the 16th Workshop on Biomedical Natural Language Processing (BioNLP)*, 2017.
- 2016 Denis R Griffis, Chaitanya Shivade, Eric Fosler-Lussier, and Albert M Lai. A Quantitative and Qualitative Evaluation of Sentence Boundary Detection for the Clinical Domain. In *Proceedings of the AMIA Summit on Clinical Research Informatics* (AMIA-CRI), 2016.

#### Posters and Presentations

2017 Denis Newman-Griffis, Thanh Thieu, Chunxiao Zhou, Diane Brandt, Jonathan Camacho Maldonado, Julia Porcino, Albert M Lai, and Leighton Chan. Characterizing the language of functioning: A corpus analysis illustrating how human function is described in clinical text. Poster presentation, in *Proceedings of the AMIA Summit on Clinical Research Informatics (AMIA-CRI)*, 2017.

#### Education

2014— **PhD student**, *The Ohio State University, Department of Computer Science and Engineering*, Columbus, OH, USA.

Modeling and extracting information regarding patient function from clinical text. Co-advised by Dr. Eric Fosler-Lussier and Dr. Albert Lai (now of Washington University in St. Louis)

2008–2012 Bachelor of Arts, Carleton College, City, Magna cum laude.

Majors: Computer Science & Russian

- o Senior thesis (Computer Science) titled "PIG: Packet Inspection Guru."
- Senior thesis (Russian): translation of Georgiy Demidov's short story, "No Toe Tag," published in the short story collection, "Five Fates from a Wondrous Planet" (2015).

# **Fellowships**

2015- **Pre-Doctoral Fellow**, *National Institutes of Health, Clinical Center*.

# Professional Experience

2012–2014 Software Developer, Fulcrum Software Solutions, Dublin, OH, USA.

Designed, developed, and deployed applications in the business and healthcare sectors, using the .NET development stack.

• Acted as client contact for design and troubleshooting on multiple projects.

#### Service

# Departmental Service

2015 Al Seminar Coordinator, The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH, USA. Coordinated bi-weekly seminar series for student presentations on ongoing Al research at Ohio State.

#### Reviewer

2017 ACL, AMIA, EMNLP

2016 ACL, AMIA

#### Other

2014– **Volunteer Judge**, *Ohio State Science Day*.

Judged science fair projects of students grades 5–12.

2016–2017 President, Columbus Symphony Chorus, Columbus, OH, USA.

# Affiliations

ACM Association for Computing Machinery

AMIA American Medical Informatics Association

ASEE American Society for Engineering Education